# Ann-Marie <u>Foerste</u>r

# Web & Graphic Designer

I am a creative individual with over four years of multi-platform web and graphic design experience. I focus on creating accessible projects with budget and scale in mind. I treat every project as a learning experience or a way to see a new perspective.

## **Skills**

- · Mac and PC Platforms
- · Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, and Dreamweaver
- · HTML and CSS3
- · Responsive web design
- · GitHub and GitHub Desktop
- · WordPress and Drupal installation and management
- · Print design and layouts for flyers, ads, and floor signs

### Education

#### **The Ohio State University**

September 2009 - December 2013 Bachelor of Fine Arts in Art & Technology

A fine arts program in art and technology. Learned art and design fundamentals as well as color theory, photography, image & video editing, 3D modeling and animation, and web design. Primary programs used were Adobe Creative Suite, Maya, Cinema4D, and Apple programs. Complimentary minor was in film studies, focusing on film history and world cinema.

2692 Hibbert Avenue
Columbus, OH 43202
614-306-5602
ann\_foerster@hotmail.com
linkedin.com/in/annmariefoerster
annmariefoerster.com/

# **Experience**

#### **Conrads College Gifts**

August 2017 - December 2019, Designer May 2015 - November 2016, Intern

- Gave the business a digital voice with assistance on a Drupal Commerce site and social media presence. Integrated Facebook business for conversion tracking. Changes saved the company around \$1,500 a month.
- Brought products to life with image editing in Photoshop and product descriptions. Editing included background, packaging, and glare removal, color correction, and relevant stock photo use for life use product photos.
- Made online banners, print ads, and social media content.
- Training of two interns, especially with the creation of gift catalogues and mailed flyers.

#### **Freelance and Relevant Personal Projects**

July 2011 - Present, Freelance Designer

- Branding, SEO, and content creation for an illustration portfolio. WordPress and social media account management. Photoshop is used for ads, posters, and product templates. Management of an ecommerce platform with Woocommerce with original products and print on demand through API connections.
- Created HTML and CSS web pages for the online presence of small businesses.
- Assisted with image editing in Photoshop.
- Assisted with the expedited layout and design of product flyers for Flairsoft, a local software company.

#### JPMorgan & Chase through Randstad

November 2016 - July 2017, Web Design Consultant

- Brought on to assist with a vocabulary reassignment project to completion, which was successfully completed on time.
- Used Dreamweaver to proof HTML procedural pages for working links, new and retiring copy, and adherence to the company style guidelines.
- Tracked tickets through Sharepoint, Excel, and page comments with dates, initials, and ticket numbers.
- Repair and update Word pages as needed or when there was free time.